Forever.
Black Panther: Wakanda Forever is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Ryan Coogler.
Queen Ramonda, Shuri, M’Baku, Okoye and the Dora Milaje fight to protect their nation
from intervening world powers in the wake of King T’Challa’s death.
As the Wakandans strive to embrace their next chapter, the heroes must band together with the help
of War Dog Nakia and Everett Ross and forge a new path for the kingdom of Wakanda.
Shuri, played by Letitia Wright.
Namor, played by Tenoch Huerta Mejía.
Nakia, played by Lupita Nyong'o.
Okoye, played by Danai Gurira.
M'Baku, played by Winston Duke.
Ramonda, played by Angela Bassett.
Black Panther: Wakanda Forever is a 2022 American superhero film based on
Marvel Comics featuring the character Shuri / Black Panther.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the sequel
to Black Panther (2018) and the 30th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Directed by Ryan Coogler, who co-wrote the screenplay with Joe Robert Cole, the film stars Letitia Wright as Shuri / Black Panther, alongside Lupita Nyong'o, Danai Gurira,
Winston Duke, Florence Kasumba, Dominique Thorne, Michaela Coel, Mabel Cadena, Tenoch Huerta Mejía, Martin Freeman, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, and Angela Bassett.
In the film, the leaders of Wakanda fight to protect their
nation in the wake of King T'Challa's death.
Ideas for a sequel began after the release of Black Panther in February 2018.
Coogler negotiated to return as director in the following months, and Marvel
Studios officially confirmed the sequel's development in mid-2019.
Plans for the film changed in August 2020 when Black Panther star and T'Challa actor Chadwick
Boseman died from colon cancer, with Marvel choosing not to recast his role.
The return of other main cast members from the first film was confirmed that November, and the
sequel's title was revealed to be Black Panther: Wakanda Forever in May 2021.
Filming began in late June in Atlanta, taking place at both Trilith Studios and Tyler Perry Studios, before moving to
Massachusetts in August, but was halted in November to allow Wright to recover from an injury sustained during filming.
It resumed by mid-January 2022 and wrapped in late March in Puerto Rico.
Black Panther: Wakanda Forever premiered at the El Capitan Theatre and the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on October
26, 2022, and was released in the United States on November 11, as the final film in Phase Four of the MCU.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $859.2
million worldwide, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2022.
Wakanda Forever and Bassett's performance received numerous awards and nominations, including five Academy Awards (winning Costume Design), one British
Academy Film Award, six Critics' Choice Movie Awards (winning two), two Golden Globe Awards (winning one), and two Screen Actors Guild Awards.
A spin-off miniseries focusing on Thorne's Riri
Williams, Ironheart, premiered in June 2025.
A sequel is in development for an expected 2028 release.
The film explores themes of hero, loss of loved one,
superhero, royal family, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.